hi spring fans welcome to another
嗨，春季粉丝们欢迎来到另一个
installment of spring tips in this
在此安装弹簧提示
installment we're going to look at the
分期付款，我们将看看
solution to a very common problem
解决一个非常普遍的问题
something that I grant you is a little
我给你的东西有点
bit of a sort of small corner case in
有点小角落的情况
the ecosystem but one that none of s
生态系统，但没有一个
kind of intrigues a lot of people who
引起很多人的兴趣
start to think about it which is how do
开始考虑这是怎么做的
i propagate state across the sort of
我将状态传播到
different stages of a reactive pipeline
反应管道的不同阶段
so think about what happens here in the
因此，请考虑一下这里发生的情况
reactive world in stark contrast to the
与之形成鲜明对比的反应世界
more traditional approaches to to
更传统的方法
handling what web requests into a and to
处理将什么Web请求放入和
addressing those kinds of concerns in
解决这些问题
the reactive world code it's not
反应性世界代码不是
guaranteed to execute on a given thread
保证在给定线程上执行
so this is as I say different than what
所以这就是我所说的与
you might have expected when using the
您可能在使用
reactive sorry the non reactive code in
对不起，非反应性代码在
for example a servlet engine in a
例如，
servlet engine you have a unless you
servlet引擎，除非您有
specify otherwise by default it's one
否则默认指定是一个
thread per request so a request comes in
每个请求的线程数，因此有一个请求
and there's a thread that's hosting that
并且有一个线程托管
request and the response that gets
请求和得到的响应
produced for that request and that all
为该要求而生产的
happens in the context of a single
发生在单个环境中
thread and so machinery you know a
线程等机械，您知道一个
mechanisms that we are with with which
我们所使用的机制
we are accustomed things like thread
我们已经习惯了线程
locals those serve us well in those use
那些在我们的服务中为我们服务的当地人
cases but they start to fall apart as
案件，但他们开始崩溃
soon as you introduce a synchronicity
引入同步性后
that is to say the possibility that work
也就是说工作的可能性
will hop to a different thread of
会跳到另一个线程
execution this is a very real
执行是非常真实的
possibility in the world of reactive
反应世界的可能性
programming where execution can very
可以执行的编程
easily very often hop threads of a you
很容易经常跳一个你的线程
know hop from one thread to another in
知道从一个线程跳到另一个线程
the in the process of producing a
在生产过程中
response so how do we solve this and we
回应，那么我们如何解决这个问题，我们
do need to solve this right this is this
确实需要解决这个问题，这是这个
is something that has to be solved in
是必须解决的问题
order to address things like transaction
为了解决诸如交易之类的问题
management and demarcation until in
管理和划分直到
order to address things like security
为了解决诸如安全之类的问题
context propagation right these are
上下文传播权这些是
things that spring itself relies upon at
春天本身依赖的东西
lower levels but with which you may not
较低的级别，但您可能没有
have to directly interact it's a concern
必须直接互动这是一个问题
with it you may not have to directly
有了它，您可能不必直接
interact but that needs to be addressed
互动，但需要解决
right today we're going to look at that
今天我们要去看看
mechanism it's called the reactor
叫做反应堆的机制
context
语境
so build an application called the
因此构建一个名为
weirdest use we're just gonna use the
最奇怪的用途，我们只是要使用
reactive web support here nothing else
反应式网络支持
Oh Lombok weasel I'm back to make my
哦，龙目鼬鼠，我要回来做我的
life a little easier well hit generate
生活好一点好命中产生
that'll give us a new zip file which
这会给我们一个新的zip文件
I'll I'll then open up here we go and
我会在这里打开我们去的
we're gonna demonstrate a very simple
我们将展示一个非常简单的
example first we're gonna demonstrate
首先我们要示范
just you know a simple rest endpoint
只要你知道一个简单的休息终点
that produces some data and we'll take a
产生一些数据，我们将采取
look at how we can use that data okay so
看看我们如何使用这些数据，好吧
let's suppose in our basic application
让我们假设在我们的基本应用程序中
this is we're gonna build an application
这是我们要构建的应用程序
let's just get rid of this one get rid
让我们摆脱这一个摆脱
of the basic one here I'll create one
我将在这里创建一个基本的
called well let's see we want to create
好吧，让我们看看我们要创建
a package I suppose okay it that first
一个包装，我想首先
so simple and then in the simple package
如此简单，然后放在简单包装中
when you've got a new class called
当你有一个新的班级叫做
the simple application alright and this
简单的应用程序还可以
will just be just like any other
就像其他任何东西一样
springboard application it'll be a
跳板的应用程序将是
public static void main okay
公共静态无效主要还可以
orgs and I appreciate that IntelliJ is
组织，我感谢IntelliJ是
trying to remind me after 25 years that
想在25年后提醒我
I should I should have the brackets next
我应该下一个括号
to the type instead of the argument
类型而不是参数
variable name like that which is what
像这样的变量名
I've been doing so if I do that it gives
如果这样做，我一直在这样做
me the yellow highlight I'll run there
我那黄色的亮点，我会去那里
around the variable name thank you
周围的变量名谢谢
and I've been doing that because I came
我一直这样做是因为我来了
from C so sorry background so anyway
来自C，所以很抱歉，所以无论如何
spring application dot run simple
春季应用程序点运行简单
application dot class and what we're
应用程序点类以及我们
gonna do is very simple when the
当
application starts up we're gonna have a
应用程序启动，我们将有一个
rest endpoint so we're gonna call this
其余端点，所以我们将其称为
just data and we're going to return some
只是数据，我们将返回一些
data okay and that data will come from a
数据还可以，数据将来自
publisher when you create that publisher
创建发布者时的发布者
in a second we want this to be a rest
一秒钟我们希望这是休息
controller of course so we'll say at
控制器，当然，我们将在
rest controller
休息控制器
and we're just going to provide some
我们将提供一些
data so where do I get that publisher
数据，那么我从哪里获得该发布商
well a flux of screen now keep in mind
现在要记住屏幕的变化
this is a reactive publisher to reactive
这是被动式的发布者
stream it's gonna emit items of data
流将发出数据项
that a subscriber can then subscribe to
然后订户可以订阅
and process on different threads it may
并在不同的线程上处理
be in one nanosecond may be one year
在一纳秒内可能是一年
right there's no guarantee you any of
对，我们无法保证您
temporal sort of coupling okay so what
时间上的耦合好吗
we're gonna do is going to build a
我们要做的是建立一个
publisher that returns just let's just
返回的发布商只是
do something simple let's say when I'm
做一些简单的事情，比如说我
create a publisher that has names or
创建一个具有名称或
letters I guess you can call flux dot
字母，我猜你可以叫助焊剂点
just a B C okay and then we have a flux
只是公元前好，然后我们有一个通量
of integer all right numbers
整数的所有正确数字
flux dot just one two three all right
助焊剂点一二三好
good now we've got that now we need to
好，现在我们有了，现在我们需要
let's compose them let's say flux dot
让我们组成它们，让我们说通量点
zip numbers dot map tuple and we're
邮政编码点图元组，我们
gonna take the tuple get t1 concatenate
要带元组得到t1并置
it with a colon and tuple get t2 is this
用冒号和元组得到t2是这个
useful no but it does demonstrate where
有用，但可以说明
we're creating publishers locating
我们正在创建发布商
pipelines
管道
okay so combined and we're then gonna
好吧，如此结合，然后我们将
send that back now I want this data to I
现在发送回我想要这些数据给我
want these publishers to first of all
希望这些发布者首先
announce where they are and what on what
宣布他们在哪里，在什么地方
thread they're running and then I also
他们正在运行的线程，然后我也
want them to to possibly run on a
希望他们能够在
separate thread so I'm gonna create a
单独的线程，所以我要创建一个
method here private static flux of
此处的方法的专用静态通量
longest T okay we're just gonna have a
最长好的，我们只是要
generic parameter there okay and so
那里的通用参数还可以
we're gonna say that we want to do in
我们会说我们想做
dot do on next right so what we're gonna
点在下一个右边，所以我们要
do here is we're gonna provide a a
这里要做的是我们将提供一个
callback that gets invoked whenever
每当调用回调
there is any kind of a processing okay
可以进行任何处理
actually we get to do on each as well
其实我们也要做每件事
that's probably you know more
那也许你知道更多
interesting I don't know if that's more
有趣，我不知道还有更多吗
interesting it might be
有趣的是
yeah so let's do do one next I suppose
是的，所以我想再做一个
that says that's the first step
那是第一步
okay and when it's all we're gonna do
好吧，这就是我们要做的一切
here is we're going to consume the
这是我们要消耗的
string and then we're going to say
字符串，然后我们要说
subscribe on and we're going to
订阅，我们将要
subscribe on a custom scheduler well the
订阅自定义调度程序
question then of course is what stitch
问题是，当然是什么针
what scheduler so I'm going to create
什么调度程序，所以我要创建
one I guess or means final but scheduler
我猜测或表示最终的但计划程序
scheduler equals scheduler dot from
调度程序等于来自的调度程序点
executors executors dot new fix thread
执行者执行者点新的修复线程
pool alright there you go so there's my
游泳池好了，你去，所以有我的
new scheduler and I'm cutting a custom
新的调度程序，我正在削减自定义
schedule should you ever do this
安排你是否应该这样做
probably not right most of the time your
大多数时候可能不正确
scheduler will be the default one which
调度程序将是默认的
is backed by the number of by a number
由数字支持
of threads that corresponds to the
对应于
number of cores you've got and each one
您拥有的核心数，每个核心
acts as an event loop and so long as no
充当事件循环，只要没有
none of your processing monopolizes the
您的任何处理都不会垄断
thread on which is running that's to say
正在运行的线程
it doesn't do anything along with and
它并没有做任何事情
takes to switch to the i/o then you
需要切换到I / O，然后您
don't really need this right don't need
真的不需要这种权利不需要
to manage this but if you are doing
管理这个，但是如果你在做
something with JDBC or something that
JDBC之类的东西
blocks otherwise like Fibonacci or
阻止斐波那契或
cryptography or Bitcoin or whatever that
密码学或比特币或其他
work should be done on a you know you
你应该在一个你知道的工作上完成工作
have to scale out that interaction by
必须扩大互动
having more threads and so it might
有更多的线程，所以它可能
become useful to do this in this case
在这种情况下变得有用
I'm just gonna provide extra threads
我只是要提供额外的线程
alright so there we go I'm overriding
好了，所以我们去了
I'm changing the incoming publisher by
我正在通过以下方式更改即将到来的发布者
first of all configuring that I want to
首先我要配置
log out information I'm going to log out
注销信息我要注销
that information by using any log4j
通过使用任何log4j获得该信息
longer that'll plug in okay so long time
更长的时间，可以插入那么长的时间
info T and of course this could be
信息T，当然这可能是
written as a lambda and that can be
写成lambda，可以是
written as root method reference like so
像这样写为根方法参考
alright very good so that's not too bad
很好，那还不错
so we're gonna say prepare all right one
所以我们要说准备好一个
and prepare
并准备
and there we go okay and there's my
然后我们就可以了，还有我的
combined you know
结合你知道
pre-processed to publisher and I'm just
预处理到发布者，我只是
gonna be turn the combined one all right
会把合并的那一转
so now let's just say we say we turn
所以现在让我们说我们转身
read all right and now we can restart
阅读所有权利，现在我们可以重新启动
this application let's see what we get
这个应用程序让我们看看我们得到了什么
go go go suppose we can inline this
去吧去吧，假设我们可以内联
while fiddling around here good
同时在这里闲逛好
until today still thinks we have the old
直到今天仍然认为我们有旧的
one that the older public static void
一说老公共静虚
main on which we sell them we first
我们首先出售它们的主要方式
initialize the project so that's no
初始化项目，所以没有
longer true alrighty so now curl HTP
更长的时间还不错，所以现在卷曲HTP
localhost:8080 /data all right very
本地主机：8080 / data很好
simple all right there's our data and
很简单，有我们的数据，
when we log it out you can see that
当我们注销时，您可以看到
things are executing on different
事情在不同的地方执行
threads right the number is executing on
对数字执行的线程正确
thread 3 here's the combined one on
线程3这是合并的
thread 3 as well here both letters end
线程3以及两个字母都在这里结束
oh yeah that's all the letters on thread
哦，是的，所有这些字母都在线程上
2 and here is 3 for the numbers but here
2，这里是3，但是这里
is thread for for the combined one so it
是组合的线程，所以它
was on thread 3 so they combined one and
在线程3上，所以他们将一个与
then it was on come on thread forward so
然后就在线程前进中，所以
you can see that the scheduler based on
您可以看到基于
whatever criteria it needs to it moves
无论它需要什么标准
work around different threads and that's
围绕不同的线程工作，那就是
that's one of the features right over
这是正确的功能之一
the reactive API alright but that does
响应式API可以，但是可以
make things a bit more complicated that
使事情变得更加复杂
means that we can't take for granted
意味着我们不能认为是理所当然的
that if we insert something in a
如果我们在
well-known place here that that data
那个地方那个著名的数据
will then be visible and accessible to
然后将可见并可供
everything happening in this pipeline by
在这个管道中发生的一切
the by this point here right we can't
到此为止，我们不能
that we can't take that for granted
我们不能认为这是理所当然的
because while these things may look
因为虽然这些东西看起来
imperative while it may look as though
势在必行
we've written things to be sequential
我们写的东西是顺序的
they're a fact of the matter is that
他们是事实的事实是
these things could be contemporaneous
这些事情可能是同时发生的
they could be concurrent right things
他们可能并发正确的事情
might be happening at the same time on
可能在同一时间发生
different threads and so we need to to
不同的线程，所以我们需要
rely of punch some other mechanism one
依靠其他一些机制
way to do that is to provide a
做到这一点的方法是提供一个
subscriber context okay now though I can
订阅者上下文现在可以了，虽然我可以
text is an object is it's just a
文字是一个对象，它只是一个
dictionary basically it's a dictionary
字典基本上是字典
that you have access to in in your
您有权访问的
pipeline that that reactor will take
该反应堆将采用的管道
care to perpetuate for you right and the
关心为您永存权利，
benefit of that is that you can make
这样做的好处是您可以
this data available you can make this
这些数据可用，您可以做到这一点
data
数据
available at the very beginning of the
在一开始就可用
pipeline and even if it moves across
管道，即使它跨过
different thread boundaries it'll be
不同的线程边界
visible only to the stages in that
仅对那个阶段可见
pipeline
管道
it doesn't matter which thread it's
不管是哪个线程
running on so we can use that to
运行，所以我们可以用它来
propagate for example you know
传播例如你知道
application tokens and headers and three
应用程序令牌和标头以及三个
authentication principles and
认证原则和
transactions and you know whatever thing
交易，你知道什么
you want to be accessible for a lifetime
您希望一生都可以访问
of a given publisher okay so let's do
一个给定的发行商，好吧，让我们做
that we're gonna we have here this
我们要在这里
prepare method let's just try it with
准备方法，让我们尝试一下
just this one okay so I'm going to give
只是这个还行，所以我要给
this a subscriber context okay I'm gonna
这是一个订户上下文，好吧，我要
say subscriber context and my job is
说订户上下文，我的工作是
very simple given a context return the
给定一个上下文非常简单的返回
context and I can do whatever I want
我可以做任何我想做的事
with the context that can change it I
可以改变它的环境
can override it I can contribute to it
可以覆盖它，我可以为它做贡献
etc etc etc that's one option and you
等等等，这是一个选择，你
know works for me I could actually do a
知道对我有用，我实际上可以做一个
set or app or whatever another option is
设置或应用或其他任何选项
to instead just provide the reference
只是提供参考
itself using the convenient builder
本身使用方便的构建器
method so here I can say context will be
方法，所以在这里我可以说上下文是
UID you know this would be my off ID or
UID，您知道这将是我的关闭ID或
whatever okay your user ID there we go
好的，您的用户名就可以了
let's let's see and then we can actually
让我们来看看，然后我们实际上可以
store UID dot random to string never go
将UID点随机存储到字符串永不消失
that's a random string now that context
那是一个随机的字符串
will be visible inside the inside the
将在里面的内部可见
stages of this pipeline
该管道的各个阶段
so let's actually add that pipeline
所以我们实际上添加该管道
that's actually now you know cuz we've
实际上，现在您知道因为我们
seen that the combined letters can
看到合并的字母可以
execute across different threads so now
跨不同的线程执行，所以现在
let's prove that out let's say do on
让我们证明说吧
each okay so I'm gonna put a consumer
每一个都行，所以我要放一个消费者
that will consume a signal and here the
这将消耗一个信号，在这里
signal is a representation of what
信号代表什么
method was a called was it the on next
方法被称为是下一步吗
was it on subscribe etc so signal no I
是否在订阅等，所以信号不我
say if signal dot is on next right or
说出信号点是否在下一个右边或
put another way if it's not on next then
如果不在下一个地方则放另一种方式
return now otherwise we want to process
现在返回，否则我们要处理
it we want
我们想要
actually you know take the data from the
实际上，您知道从
con from the signal and so we can say
信号中的骗局，所以我们可以说
signal don't get context
信号没有上下文
okay and with that we can actually look
好的，这样我们就可以看
up the the key all right so the key is
好把钥匙放在上面，所以钥匙是
called user ID so you can say get or
称为用户ID，因此您可以说get或
default and we can say get that key all
默认，我们可以说全部获取该密钥
right there's our UID and we can log out
那里是我们的UID，我们可以注销
log info user ID for this pipeline stage
此管道阶段的日志信息用户标识
or data and then this will be signal dot
或数据，然后将是信号点
get string dot is signal is user ID
获取字符串点是信号是用户标识
weather so here I'm logging out the the
天气，所以我要登出
data that's in the on next method call
在下一个方法调用中的数据
and then I'm logging out the user ID
然后我注销用户ID
that's been perpetuated along with that
一直伴随着
with that interaction okay let's try
有了这种互动，让我们尝试
this out
这个出来
there you go
你去
look at that so now when I make the
看看那个，现在当我做
request user ID for this pipeline stage
请求此管道阶段的用户标识
for a 1 B 2 and C 3 is exactly the same
1 B 2和C 3完全相同
thing now keep in mind this one these
现在记住这些
are both on thread 10 these are both and
都在线程10上
you know different threads so you can
你知道不同的线程，所以你可以
see we have the fact that these things
看到我们有一个事实，这些东西
are being moved across different roads
正在穿越不同的道路
this is 9 that's a 1 and here's the same
这是9那是1，这是一样的
thing thread 9
物线9
so that's here's thread 10 for the B 2 C
这是B 2 C的线程10
3 is on beat is on 10 as well okay
3拍就10
pretty straightforward right I mean you
非常简单的权利，我是说你
can kind of see what's happening here we
可以看到这里发生了什么
just use the subscriber context to
只需使用订户上下文
create a context object which acts as
创建一个充当
basically a dictionary and you can see
基本上是一本字典，你可以看到
that of there's a bunch of them here you
那里有一堆你
know that you can that you can work with
知道你可以和你一起工作
or you could provide a transforming
或者你可以提供一个转变
function that takes the current context
需要当前上下文的函数
and you can use that you could a new
你可以用你可以一个新的
context that has the existing values
具有现有值的上下文
from the existing context and that also
从现有环境中
has new values that when our insert in
有新值，当我们插入
there okay so that's the the theoretical
好的，那是理论上的
and this is used to great effect in
这在
spring for example in in spring security
春天，例如在春季安全中
right so if you go to spring security
对，所以如果你去春季安全
here we're gonna look for the the
在这里，我们要寻找
reactor context web filter reactor
反应堆环境腹板过滤器
context web filters security okay and
上下文网络过滤器安全性还可以，
that's there you go and this code for
在那里，您可以使用此代码
example is in spring security in the
例子是春季安全
integration for reactive code and this
集成反应式代码和此
is actually a reactive web filter right
实际上是一个反应式网页过滤器
this is a spring what web flex filter
这是一个弹簧什么web柔韧性过滤器
it's not a servlet filter - web flex
它不是servlet过滤器-Web Flex
filter and it in turn has a method
过滤器，它又有一个方法
called filter which takes a curtain HTTP
称为筛选器，它需要一个幕后HTTP
request and chain and we configure the
请求和链，我们配置
filter we say chained-up filter exchange
我们说的过滤器链式过滤器交换
propagating you know allowing things
传播你知道允许事情
downstream to contribute to the the
下游为
pipeline three active pipeline and then
管道三个活动管道，然后
finally at the very tail end of that we
终于在那末尾
add I subscribe a context taking the
添加我订阅一个上下文
current context checking to see if it
当前的上下文检查，看是否
has a key if it does then we turn it
有一个钥匙，如果有的话，我们把它打开
otherwise we create a new context or
否则，我们将创建一个新的上下文或
actually which alter the context by
实际上是哪个改变了上下文
adding the security context to it so
向其添加安全上下文
they react so the spring security
他们做出反应，所以春季安全
security context is a thing that holds
安全上下文是一件事
the currently authenticated user so when
当前经过身份验证的用户，因此
you make a HTTP post or a form based
您发布HTTP帖子或基于表单
login that information gets passed to
登录以将信息传递给
some sort of authentication manager
某种身份验证管理器
which then either confirms the you know
然后要么确认您知道
it confirms that this is the person or
它确认这是那个人或
client or whatever that is claiming it
客户或任何声称自己的客户
you know that it is claiming to be and
你知道它自称是
if that's the case it then stashes that
如果是这样的话，那就藏起来
resulting authentication object
结果认证对象
somewhere well that's the security
安全的地方
context holder and in turn that's the
上下文持有者，那就是
context that's made available through
通过以下方式提供的上下文
this filter at the very beginning of all
这个过滤器在所有的开始
web requests in spring web flex so now
Web请求在Spring Web Flex中出现，所以现在
anywhere in your code in spring security
Spring Security中代码中的任何地方
you can inject the current authenticated
您可以注入当前经过身份验证的
principal because spring security can
校长，因为春季安全可以
look at the current pipeline that's been
看一下当前的管道
modified by this reactive web filter and
通过此反应式Web过滤器修改并
look at the context and extract out this
查看上下文并提取出来
object of type of security context our
安全上下文类型的对象
class that's the other thing I'm using a
类是我正在使用的另一件事
key here but imagine I wanted to store
关键在这里，但想像我想存储
some more interesting kind of data I
一些更有趣的数据
could say stat you know class user ID
可以说您知道课程用户ID的统计信息
all right and I can do something like
好的，我可以做类似的事情
this
这个
I'm string UID well certainly you know I
我是UID字符串，当然您知道吗
could do that and that would be here I
可以做到，那将在我身边
can say instead of using a key I can use
可以说而不是使用钥匙
the class type right I can stash that
正确的班级类型
and have that perpetuated along with the
并将其与
the pipeline as well obviously it'd be a
管道也很明显
smaller the data the better but the
数据越小越好，但是
point is you can do both okay all right
关键是你们都可以做得很好
so that's a very simple abstract idea
所以这是一个非常简单的抽象想法
and I hope with spring security you can
我希望春季安全可以
see the possible applications now let's
现在查看可能的应用程序
be a little bit more concrete here I'm
我在这里更具体一点
gonna take an example taken directly not
要直接举一个例子
even like I'm not even gonna bother
甚至我都不会打扰
writing this I don't even have to write
写这个，我什至不必写
this you know myself I didn't even have
这你知道我自己，我什至没有
to imagine this there's a great example
想象这是一个很好的例子
by reactor team legend
由反应堆团队传奇
the reactor reactive ninja
反应堆反应忍者
extraordinaire seaman Bosley that is
非凡的海员博斯利
from C Mon Bosley contextual logging
从C Mon Bosley上下文记录
let's see if I can find this this
让我们看看我是否可以找到这个
amazing book okay so this blog from
很棒的书好吧，所以这个博客来自
earlier this year looks at using the MDC
今年早些时候着眼于使用MDC
looking at the reactive context object
看反应上下文对象
and using it as a way to perpetuate the
并以此作为使
MDC there the context that's made
MDC在那里的背景
available for logging so when you log
可用于记录，因此当您登录时
out stuff in your logs you have
删除日志中的内容
information keys and values that can be
信息键和值可以是
associated with that log that has
与具有
traditionally historically been based on
传统上一直基于
that thread local and so in this blog
该线程本地，因此在此博客中
Simone looks at how to to you know
西蒙妮看着你怎么知道
rework things for ever so slightly to
返工永远如此微小
take advantage of the new context object
利用新的上下文对象
in reactor so I'm just gonna show you
在反应堆中，所以我要告诉你
that that's actually what we're gonna
那实际上就是我们要做的
see next it's a very simple example and
接下来看，这是一个非常简单的示例，
it demonstrates things beautifully
它很好地展示了事物
beautifully so I I'm rather than do
非常漂亮，所以我不是
something completely different which
完全不同的东西
would fail to meet the standard that he
达不到他的标准
is said I'm just gonna use that so we're
据说我只是要用那个所以我们
gonna create a very simple MDC
要创建一个非常简单的MDC
application and this application it's
应用程序，这个应用程序是
going to be a Springwood application
将成为Springwood应用程序
it's going to be I'm gonna have a logger
这将是我要有一个记录器
and it'll be a rescue core and what
它将成为救援的核心
we're gonna do is we're going to
我们要去做的是
demonstrate that we can respond to an
证明我们可以回应
HTTP request and in providing that
HTTP请求并提供
response we can associate information
回应，我们可以关联信息
with the request that gets visible
与可见的请求
that's then made available to the
然后将其提供给
logging context name the logging master
日志记录上下文名称日志记录主机
data context okay so what I'm gonna do
数据上下文好吧，我该怎么办
now is create a service just as he did a
现在就像他做了一个
restaurant service and the service come
餐厅服务，服务来了
on
上
the service will provide a answer to the
该服务将为
question of which restaurants come he
他去哪家餐馆的问题
gives it visit by max price all right
允许其以最高价格访问
there we go and we'll just use a double
我们去了，我们将使用双
and price all right and when I'm a
和价格好，当我是
detail here class restaurant double
这里的细节双人间餐厅
price for
价格
person private string name all right
人私有字符串名称可以
this would be public static void main
这将是公共静态无效主体
wouldn't get very far without that I
没有我，我不会走的太远
expect all right spring application
期待所有春季申请
spring application got run MDC
春季应用程序运行MDC
application dot class ARDS very good so
应用点类ARDS非常好，所以
there we go there's that right now what
我们去那里那就是现在
are we gonna do we provide a application
我们会提供申请吗
that has constructors all right and
有好的构造函数，
we're going to return the data when we
我们将在我们返回数据时
turn the data here and the data we're
在这里把数据和我们的数据
just gonna have some hard coded data I'm
只是会有一些硬编码的数据
gonna just hard quote some data because
只会引用一些数据，因为
I don't actually have a database
我实际上没有数据库
connected to this though of course it's
虽然与此有关
all reactive so we could talk to our to
都是被动的，所以我们可以和我们交谈
UBC we could use a reactive MongoDB you
UBC我们可以使用反应式MongoDB您
could use reactive Couchbase or
可以使用反应性Couchbase或
Cassandra or Redis anything would work
Cassandra或Redis一切正常
just fine but I am just gonna synthesize
很好，但我只是要综合
some data for our demo in the
演示中的一些数据
constructor here and in order to do that
构造函数在这里，为了做到这一点
I am going to create a collection of
我将创建一个集合
data a hard coded response okay private
数据的硬编码响应好私有
final collection
最终收藏
okay restaurant restaurants equals you
好的餐馆餐馆等于你
concurrent skip this set all righty
并发跳过此设置
and that has to be comparable so we'll
那必须是可比的，所以我们将
set new compare tour I'm gonna say oh
设定新的比较巡演，我要说哦
one get price the person I'm going to do
一个要价的人我要去做
double one to the turn one compared to
与第一回合相比加倍
two
二
alright and we'll create that collection
好吧，我们将创建该集合
and in the collection we're just gonna
在集合中，我们将
have some data I'm just gonna write some
有一些数据我要写一些
beta the old-fashioned way by generating
通过生成旧式的beta
it's all say I'm in stream dot I guess I
都是说我在流点中
just want to build a range let's just
只是想建立一个范围而已
build a range zero to a thousand two
建立从零到十二的范围
objects I I integer to string restaurant
对象II整数到字符串餐厅
I okay so that of my string Oh
我可以，这样就可以了
okay new restaurant and it'll be a
好吧，新餐厅，它将是一个
double so we'll say new random dot next
加倍，所以我们接下来要说新的随机点
double I don't dot 100 okay and then the
双倍我不加点100好，然后
name will be string and then for each
名称将是字符串，然后是每个
one of those I guess we can just we want
我想我们可以只是想要的其中之一
to set that as a we're gonna add that to
设置为a我们将其添加到
the collection there so for each this
那里的每个收藏
dot restaurant collection and right okay
点餐厅集合，好吗
seems very straightforward okay so we're
似乎很简单，所以我们
just gonna start up the application in
只是要在中启动应用程序
the constructor we're gonna write a
我们要写的构造函数
bunch of records to that collection
一堆记录到那个集合
which is gonna be comparable it's
这将是可比的
optimized for reading that for writing
为阅读而优化
that's why it's it's no it's probably
这就是为什么不是
not a great fit but whatever it's a demo
不太适合，但无论是演示
okay very simple demo and this is no
好吧，非常简单的演示，这不是
longer true good restaurants okay so
更长的真正的好餐厅还可以，所以
there's our data now here's our
这是我们的数据，这是我们的
publisher here's our reactive endpoint
发布者，这是我们的反应性终点
and we're gonna say assuming that we
我们要说的是
find a record when say get the data this
查找记录时说要获取数据
dot this dot restaurants dot hello
点这个点餐厅点你好
stream so if I suppose filter when you
流，如果我想当你过滤
say restaurant and then that will be
说餐厅，那将是
when I say restaurant doctor kit price
当我说餐厅医生套件价格时
per person less than or equal to max
每人小于或等于最大
price right so that'll be a stream of
价格合适，这样就可以
restaurant that matches our predicate
符合我们谓词的餐厅
here okay
好的
simple and from that we can get a
简单，从中我们可以得到一个
publisher so flex dot from stream is
发布者，因此流中的flex点是
okay so that's the that's the basic demo
好的，那就是基本的演示
okay that's pretty simple right we're
好的，那很简单，我们
gonna create a little rest controller
要创建一个休息控制器
here just in case to have been that data
以防万一是那个数据
so user ID you know crisis whatever
所以您知道用户ID的危机
restaurants restaurants let's just make
餐馆餐馆让我们来做
this easy okay so I'm gonna assume a
这很容易，所以我要假设
price as a category as a as a as a
价格作为一个类别作为一个作为
discriminator here but I want the user
区分这里，但我希望用户
ID information to be visible in the life
生活中可见的ID信息
of the of the request so I'm going to
的要求，因此我将
say that this is the path variable and
说这是路径变量，
you can use request parameters as well
您也可以使用请求参数
it doesn't matter here and the double
没关系，在这里，双
will be path variable double price
将是路径变量的两倍价格
alright so we want to inject the
好吧，所以我们想注入
restaurant service like so and then
像这样的餐厅服务
already they turned this docked
他们已经把这个停靠了
restaurant service dot get by max price
餐厅服务点以最高价获得
price and I want that context when I log
价格，我想在登录时使用该上下文
out the information in this publisher in
在此发布者中获取信息
this reactive publisher what I want to
这个被动的发布者我想
do is I want to log out information
我要注销信息吗
about the search then I want to log out
关于搜索，然后我想注销
the results of the search and then I
搜索的结果，然后我
want to log out the current you know the
想注销当前知道的
current application ID so let's now
当前的应用程序ID，现在让我们
transform our little publisher here okay
在这里改变我们的小出版商
so private static lot specific to that
因此专用于此的私人静态批次
okay teeth consumer key log on next and
好的，牙齿消费者密钥登录下一步，然后
this will be a consumer long statement
这将是消费者的长期声明
okay so there's my I am my handler and
好吧，所以有我我是我的经理，
what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna change
我要做的就是改变
this I'm gonna change you know avoid
这我要改变你知道避免
adapt the results okay so I want to take
调整结果好吧，所以我想
the flux of restaurants in and we'll do
餐馆的变化，我们会做
work with it so I want to say adapt you
使用它，所以我想说适应您
could do this with a filter certainly
可以肯定用过滤器做到这一点
results and I will return a flux of
结果，我将返回
restaurant as before and here's we're
和以前一样的餐厅，这是我们
gonna do all the work of sort of
会做所有的工作
changing this result so I'm gonna say
改变这个结果，所以我要说
first return mono dot just strained
第一次返回单点只是紧张
format so I want to log out the
格式，所以我要注销
beginning of the pipeline finding the
管道开始寻找
restaurants and I guess we can actually
餐厅，我想我们实际上可以
um
嗯
passing the price UID and the price okay
传递价格UID和价格还可以
string double price having price lower
串双价，价格更低
then okay so the dollar sign for that
那好吧，所以美元符号
user ID okay and then when you string
用户ID正确，然后在您输入字符串时
that format so UID
这样的格式，所以UID
that's right price UID and from there
正确的价格UID，然后从那里开始
I'm going to say do on each and I'm
我要说的是做每个，我是
gonna log out the results that come back
要注销返回的结果
so log on next and this will just be on
所以先登录，然后就可以了
in the consumer that I pass into this
在我传递给它的消费者中
method all I'm gonna do is log and with
我要做的就是日志和
that I'll then say I want to get the
然后我会说我想得到
results
结果
so restaurant service start get my max
所以餐厅服务开始让我最大
price and actually we already have that
价格，实际上我们已经有了
don't be so I don't need to redo the
别这样，我不需要重做
search we just pass that along okay and
搜索，我们只是将其传递通过，然后
then from there I want to log some more
然后从那里我想记录更多
data so I'm saying here remember the
数据，所以我在这里说的要记住
restaurant data will be what we get back
餐厅数据将是我们得到的
at this point so here I'm going to say
在这一点上，我在这里要说
log that info found restaurant for okay
记录该信息发现餐厅还可以
and then we are that get name or got to
然后我们就是那个名字或到达
get price per person and then finally
得到每人的价格，然后最终
I'm going to set the subscriber context
我将设置订户上下文
was that context of API ID and it'll be
是API ID的上下文，它将是
the UID expose that's what I'm that's
UID暴露的就是我的身份
what I really want to encode there okay
我真的想在那里编码好吗
so what's wrong with this now
所以现在怎么了
I'll do on each
我会做的每个
okay
好的
what is the problem
问题是什么
we are going to
我们准备去
ah don't want this to be a signal of T
啊，不希望这是T的信号
okay so that's gonna be a restaurant
好的，那将是一家餐厅
perfect alright so we've got that the
完美吧，所以我们已经
restaurant was a little redundant and
餐厅有点多余，
I'm fighting a problem that was real
我正在解决一个真实的问题
glad we fixed that now what I'm gonna do
很高兴我们修复了现在我要做什么
is I'm gonna say in this method this is
我要说的是这种方法
where the actual work gets done so found
找到实际工作的地方
restaurant okay it's a nice Dante an
餐厅好吧，这是一个不错的但丁
Italian with an eye so forgive me if the
意大利人用眼睛如此原谅我
spelling is all yours all right so now
拼写就没事了，所以现在
we have our simple jobs given a signal
我们给了我们简单的工作一个信号
we're gonna return a when I say if
当我说如果我们要返回一个
signal is on next or if it's not rather
信号在下一个或者不是
then just return okay but then we want
然后返回就可以了，但是我们要
to get the data out of the current
从当前数据中获取数据
context so I'm gonna say a PID like so
上下文，所以我要说这样的PID
I'm going to ask for the current context
我要询问当前的情况
get or empty and the empty when you look
得到或空着，当你看着空着
for the API ID that's a UID I suppose is
对于我认为是UID的API ID，
what we calling it and I'm gonna say
我们称之为什么，我要说
okay if that's not no we're gonna
好吧，如果不是的话，我们要
process if it's there when you use it if
使用时处理是否存在
it's not we're gonna process and I I
不是我们要去处理
made a mistake I generated this project
弄错了我生成了这个项目
using Java 1.8 but use 1111 actually
使用Java 1.8但实际上使用1111
it's a better version anyway and there's
无论如何，这是一个更好的版本，
some nice API is here that make what I
一些不错的API在这里使我
want to do here just a little bit easier
想要在这里做一点简单
okay okay so what I want to do is I want
好吧好吧所以我想做的就是我要
to say if that idea is there I'm going
说那个想法是否存在，我要去
to say give me it or an optional that's
说给我它或可选的是
empty I'm gonna say okay API ID dot if
空我要说的是API ID点
present or else so if it's there use it
目前，否则，如果它在那里使用它
otherwise run the up runnable that
否则运行可运行的
doesn't exist in java 8 but it's there
在Java 8中不存在，但是在那里
in job and 9 or 11 in this case so what
在工作中，在这种情况下为9或11，那么
I'm gonna do is I'm going to say if it's
我要说的是
there there's a consumer of string yep
有一个字符串yep的使用者
present
当下
all right and the present you know like
好吧，现在你知道的喜欢
it's there I'll say let's just say UID
我要说的就是UID
otherwise run a bull run now or else
不然现在就跑牛市
okay not bad huh
好的还不错吧
so and that runnable will be very simple
因此，可运行性将非常简单
we just say I'm gonna log the data out
我们只是说我要注销数据
let's say log statement doc accept and
假设日志语句文档接受并
I'm gonna call signal time to get some
我要打电话通知时间去买一些
logging
测井
I'm remember this method takes a
我记得这种方法需要
consumer and the consumer I'm passing in
消费者和我传递的消费者
the value that's that's been emitted and
所发出的价值，以及
I can do with it whatever I want if it's
我可以随心所欲地处理它
there however I want to take the UID and
在那里，但是我想乘UID，
attach it to the current MDC and I can
将其附加到当前的MDC，我可以
do this conveniently using the auto
使用自动方便地执行此操作
closeable feature here so there's an MDC
可关闭的功能，所以有一个MDC
closeable so I can say try closable
可以关闭，所以我可以说尝试关闭
equals MDC that put closable so it'll be
等于将MDC设为可关闭状态的MDC
alive for the scope of this demo of this
这个演示的范围还活着
interaction but no longer right that's
互动，但不再正确了
convenient so while you know inside
方便，所以当你知道里面
there let me put this up here
在那里我把它放在这里
dot run okay so it's a little confusing
点运行正常，所以有点混乱
I grant you if credit or else so let's
如果您认为我可以授予您，那么让我们
review here what's happening in this
在这里查看发生了什么事
consumer which gets run on every each
每一个都有消费的消费者
incantation I guess we could have called
咒语，我想我们可以打电话给
this on each but actually we only care
每个，但实际上我们只关心
about the on next events that's what
关于接下来的事件是什么
we're doing is we're filtering those out
我们正在做的是我们正在过滤掉那些
if we're running on an on next event or
如果我们正在运行下一个事件或
method or whatever then we look at the
方法或其他方法，然后我们看一下
current context and we ask for a that's
当前的情况，我们要求
actually just call this UID just be
实际上只是称这个UID为
consistent and in fact I could have
一致，实际上我可以
extracted all this out and I could do I
提取所有这些，我可以做
could certainly have done a better job
当然可以做得更好
here a private final static string and
这是一个私有的最终静态字符串，
would use the same key everywhere
会在各处使用相同的密钥
whether it's in the context or in my MDC
无论是在上下文中还是在我的MDC中
scope or anything else
范围或其他
okay so that'll make things a little bit
好，这样可以使事情变得一点点
simpler and I'm gonna rename this to UID
更简单，我将其重命名为UID
optional there we go okay so now we can
可选，我们可以，所以现在我们可以
see I'm gonna have some sort of UID
看到我会有某种UID
that's that's been packaged along the
那是沿着包装的
scope in packages along the life of this
整个生命周期中的包装范围
publisher and that UID I'll access here
发布商，我将在此处访问该UID
inside of this on next call back if the
如果下次在
our next method gets called then I'll
我们的下一个方法被调用，然后我会
I'll check and see if it's on next if it
我会检查它是否在下一个
is on next then I will run this block of
在下一个然后我将运行此块
code attaching the data from the current
附加当前数据的代码
context that has the UID adding it to
UID将其添加到的上下文
the current MDC context for the logger
记录器的当前MDC上下文
under the same key doesn't have to be
在相同的键下不必
the same key could be anything you want
相同的钥匙可能是您想要的任何东西
but I'm gonna attach it that way and of
但我要这样附和
course one time once it's attached then
附上课程一次
I'll run the actual thing that does the
我将运行实际的操作
work that we want to do which is the
我们想要做的工作是
callback here that the consumer that the
回调这里的消费者
client code will pass to us so I'm just
客户代码将传递给我们，所以我只是
calling logs I'm basically invoking the
调用日志，我基本上是在调用
function that somebody has given me I'm
某人给我的功能
calling I'm gonna invoke it with the
打电话给我要用
value that's been you know that's been
一直以来的价值
provided for me in the current signal in
在当前信号中为我提供
the current
目前
generation of the current value that's
当前值的生成
been emitted okay so either it's present
发射好了，所以它要么存在
either the UID is present in the reactor
反应堆中存在UID
context in which case I insert it into
在这种情况下，我将其插入
the logging MDC and then I run the
记录MDC，然后运行
consumer or it's not present in which
消费者或它不存在
case I just run the consumer but either
案例我只是经营消费者，但要么
way this has to get run it's just a
它必须运行的方式只是一个
matter of whether we set up anything
我们是否设置任何东西
inside of the Emma DMDC before we run it
在运行Emma DMDC之前
okay so that's the basic thing that sets
好，那是设定的基本要素
up the reactor context that's a found to
被发现的反应堆环境
expecting one what did I miss
期待我错过了什么
oh all right is that right looks right
哦，好吧，那权利看起来不错
there that should work okay that's
那里应该可以的
better so now the only thing that
更好，所以现在唯一的
remains of course is to set up the
剩下的当然是建立
logging pattern so that we can actually
记录模式，以便我们可以实际
see how this gets logged out and that's
看看如何注销，这就是
pretty easy to do in spring but-- so
在春天做起来很容易，但是-所以
we're just gonna customize a logging
我们只是要自定义日志记录
pattern here pattern console equals and
模式在这里模式控制台等于和
we want to say pound magenta thread cyan
我们想说磅洋红色线青色
X UID okay
X UID好
highlight five-level logger
突出显示五级记录器
36 dot M message and and there we go
36点M消息，然后我们走了
that's our our custom logger that should
这就是我们的自定义记录器
kick in so you can see up until now I've
踢，所以你可以看到直到现在我
gotten this sort of default spring boot
得到了这种默认的 spring boot
logging pattern which is fine works just
很好的记录模式
fine but we want to see that current app
很好，但我们希望看到该当前应用
ID so let's do that are the current UI e
ID，所以我们现在使用的是UI
oops ports already running applications
oops已经运行应用程序的端口
already running on the same port rather
已经在同一端口上运行
so let's stop it and restart just the
所以我们停止它并重新启动
MDC application
MDC应用
okay it's up and running and now I want
好的，它已经启动并正在运行，现在我想要
to go visit this endpoint when I say I'm
我说我去的时候去拜访这个终点
one too
也一个
and so gonna be restaurants and the
因此将成为餐馆和
price will be so we don't know what
价格将是，所以我们不知道是什么
price we have to it
我们要的价格
you should have logged out those prices
您应该已经注销了这些价格
well I suppose statistically something
好吧，我想从统计学上讲
is gonna be less than that
会小于那个
okay so JQ dot name
好吧，所以JQ点名称
it looks about right let's see
它看起来不错，让我们看看
statistically let's just see that
统计上让我们看看
smaller
较小的
yeah okay so it's diminishing if I
是的，如果我减少了
choose something you know statistically
从统计上选择您知道的东西
there's only 1% of the results is gonna
只有1％的结果会
be less than one right so so that's uh
小于一项权利，所以那是呃
that's about fine okay um less than or
大约可以，比不到还好
equal to whether and so when I make
等于当我做
these requests now let's see now I want
这些要求现在让我们看看我想要
to log out the information don't I so
登出信息不是吗
what do we have here
我们有什么在这里
log statement
日志声明
log info log info found restaurant get
日志信息日志信息找到餐厅get
name here's a thread here's the app ID
名称这里是一个线程这里是应用程序ID
right versus 1212 we have 12 restaurants
对1212与我们有12间餐厅
so now if I changes to be 15 you can see
所以现在如果我变成15岁，您可以看到
it says 15 so it's actually is so
它说15所以实际上是这样
the request with a thread it's
用线程破坏请求
very hard to sort of prove this
很难证明这一点
otherwise I mean let's see curl there
否则我的意思是让我们看看那里的卷曲
should be a little pull post hey you
应该是一个小拉发布嘿
know 20 restaurants 101 okay so there's
知道20家餐厅101好的，所以
two different sets of data I've actually
我实际上有两组不同的数据
just got two sets of results there but
那里只有两套结果，但是
now we should see 20 and 15 and so on
现在我们应该看到20和15，依此类推
okay so this is a very simple example
好的，这是一个非常简单的示例
but it does demonstrate how useful this
但这确实证明了这很有用
API is it's nice that the MDC API here
API很好，这里的MDC API
in SL 4j is so convenient you can just
SL 4j非常方便，您可以
it's an abstraction so we can easily in
这是一个抽象，所以我们可以轻松地
a generic way in certain things in the
在某些事情上的通用方式
context it's nice that we have this this
上下文很高兴我们有这个
API you can use it in other ways if you
API，您可以通过其他方式使用它
want there's I'm sure you can think of
想要有一个我确定你能想到的
things that you would like to perpetuate
您想永久保留的东西
along the lifecycle of a given reactive
沿着给定反应堆的生命周期
pipeline this is how you do that you
管道，这就是你的做法
just add things to the to the context to
只需将事物添加到上下文中即可
the subscriber context and then you can
订户上下文，然后您可以
pull those things out in either your
把那些东西拉出来
your handlers or anywhere else in the
您的经理或其他任何地方
pipeline
管道
you could stash it somewhere you could
你可以把它藏在你可以的地方
do all sorts of interesting things so my
做各种有趣的事情，所以我的
friend with that thank you so much for
的朋友，非常感谢你
watching and thank you again to seaman
看着并再次向海员表示感谢
Bosley who's got that great example it
博斯利（Bosley）有很好的榜样
was bland and for the blog which you
很平淡，对于您的博客
should all definitely go read remember
所有人都应该去读记得吗
this mechanism it underpins a lot of
这种机制支撑了很多
what we do transaction demarcation in
我们在其中进行交易划分
and security context propagation all
和安全上下文传播全部
these kinds of things that you can
这些事情，你可以
imagine wanting to do in the old in the
想像一下，想在旧时做
old world using thread locals you can
使用线程本地人的旧世界，你可以
now do in reactor and I think this is
现在在反应堆中做，我认为这是
one of those things that sets reactor
那些设置反应堆的东西之一
ahead of some of the other technologies
领先于其他一些技术
in the same sort of category the same
在同一类别中
pack because this is actually one of the
打包，因为这实际上是其中之一
things that a lot of them don't have so
很多人没有的东西
I think it's a pretty interesting place
我认为这是一个非常有趣的地方
to be alright with that with that my
与那个我的没关系
friend like I said thank you so much
像我这样的朋友非常感谢你
for watching and with that we'll see you
为了观看，我们会见到你
next time
下次
you
您